Lauren Atha BSc Biochemistry

Lauren Atha

07429 029 286

lauren.atha@yahoo.co.uk laurenatha.github.io

Summary

I'm a third year BSc Hons Biochemistry student at Lancaster University. I have gained experience in computational and laboratory techniques used in current biology research. I hope to further develop my computational skills by learning programming languages which can be used for interdisciplinary research relating to biochemistry..

Education

Lancaster University / BSc Hons Biochemistry

September 2017 - Present, LANCASTER

Predicted First- graduate in summer 2020

Modules include biochemistry, chemistry, microbiology and genetics

North Carolina State University / BSc Hons Biochemistry (Year

Abroad)

August 2018 - May 2019, NC, USA

GPA 4.0

The Blackpool Sixth Form / A Levels

September 2015 - August 2017, BLACKPOOL

A* in Maths, Biology and Chemistry

Highfield Leadership Academy / GCSEs

September 2010 - August 2015, BLACKPOOL

9 GCSEs A-A* including English, Maths and Science

Experience

University of Oxford / Internship

July 2019 - August 2019, OXFORD

6 week research project investigating the recognition of abnormal cells by leukocyte receptors.

Curvestone / Business Support

November 2017 - August 2018, LANCASTER

Provided business support for Curvestone, a company specialising in machine learning and automation, which included conducting meetings with clients, managing consultants and administrative tasks.

The Blackpool Sixth Form College / Cleaner

December 2016 - September 2017, BLACKPOOL

I worked both alone and in a team, managing my time effectively to meet the high standards of cleanliness throughout the building while following all of the COSHH procedures necessary.

Skills & Awards

I have won academic scholarships and silver and gold award in the Chemistry Olympiad and Cambridge Chemistry Challenge respectively. I've been awarded the Digital Skills Certificate from Lancaster University, and I'm proficient in Microsoft Office. I have experience in HTML and CSS which I used to create my website and am currently learning Python. I will continue to learn more programming languages in the future.

Hobbies & Interests

I enjoy playing guitar and achieved a distinction in grade 5. I like hiking so I joined the Adventure Club while I studied in America where I went on walks and hikes in state and national parks. I also enjoy reading fantasy books and have recently started learning programming languages in my spare time.